i hope you're well
just wanted to start with ferran taurus
really can you tell us exactly what's
happening is he definitely going to
barcelona if he is
why was that decision taken and does it
mean you will look to bring in a striker
in january
last question no he's not going to bring
any striker in january
second question it's not for a chickie
didn't tell me anything officially so i
cannot answer so i know they are
negotiating this i think it's close
and uh
and that's all when the club will
announce will be will be done but right
now
cheeky didn't call me didn't text me
about uh it's already already done
pep we've seen a couple of games go this
weekend already due to a rising covey
cases so just wonder now how do you feel
about carrying on with the premier
league program given that rise in cases
rather than taking a break across the
board
well raising cases all around the world
is not just in the case of premier
league so it's in everywhere
so we saw the last
feature that maybe five or six
it was postponed games so
it's a lot
and uh what the primary league and is
going to the site consulting the
managers on the people
will be good for us so
nothing to do at uh
what we want is that people stay safe
and stay well and uh please social
distance mask for everyone
because i'm surprised like the people is
saying be careful use the mask and i go
to the street and the places and and
everyone is
completely no following the
knowledge with the rules and uh we
should take care individually personally
a little bit more
you know pay attention to this kind of
things where we protect ourselves and
the rest of the people but the reality
in this new barrier is here
and
cases
are rising and uh unfortunately okay one
of premier league of football is not
exception and what they're going to
decide this afternoon the premier league
will support
and
just looking at your squad pat what
response have you seen from phil foden
and jack grealish after they didn't play
against newcastle and does their
behavior this week now warrant game time
this weekend
fernandinho
cole palmer didn't play neither
i'm just thinking of those two because
obviously they're the ones that that
made the headlines as as regards um
the fact that they were pictured on a
night out
yeah some players go out to dinner out
yeah
so it wasn't a problem it's just what
i'm trying to clarify and therefore they
could
you know feasibly be be available once
again for selecting me they were
available last week obviously but it
seems that something was built up out of
that
absolutely i'm going to clarify it man
not to you absolutely not
simon
hi
pep hope you're okay um
you kind of
um
started that debate with what you said
after the game how important is it
for a manager that they have rules that
players stick by
they are not rules i'm not a hero police
i'm not saying what they have to do
everyone is old enough
and experience enough to know exactly
what they have to do so we are living in
a special circumstances in our lives
uh that we cannot live free like we live
in the past due the pandemic situation
that is still here
and uh
and uh and everyone has to try to follow
us
you know as much as possible so we are
not alone in this world so we are living
with people you have to be careful
that's all and being carefully you can
take it
being carefully you can you know
uh
get positive so we are exposed
and uh just be careful that's all and we
spoke about that from a long time ago
um you mentioned the managers meeting
you you've spoken a lot
about your thoughts about the calendar
and
nobody nobody really listens
do you think the premier league are
going to actually listen because
most of the managers will think exactly
the same thing won't they they'll think
there's too many games why can't we have
five substitutes why
you are more experienced than me you are
a
uk person
you have you
were born here
so
the the tradition from boxing days in
the football in the premier league is
massively important is
is one of the characteristics that's why
this leak is especially in this time of
period this is not going to be changed
so
and i would say i said many times
i would love not change
to play
in this period a lot of games i'm not
the proof to play after two days but
after three days
because it's tradition one century ago
two centuries ago
uh premier league always the boxing days
was so important it was so nice for the
families go to the altogether to the
stadium that can imagine
first of january in in in london arsenal
man city 12 30 how nice will be the
stadium with all the people
so it's so nice the problem is the
fixtures the calendars that 365 days a
year
with the international duties for the
national teams for the
huge competitions for a lot of games
this is the problem as we solve the play
as i said many times have two weeks
three weeks holidays in summertime
that's all and season again two three
weeks and again and again this is too
much that is not too much for this
period for one week ten days now of
course the situation that we know
exactly for
five six uh games postponed
from many many uh cases in many many
teams
yeah that happened one year ago it
happened quite similar or two years ago
quite similar again so yeah it's it's
it's the reality and maybe you have to
adapt the situation
what is going to happen the next weeks
but this afternoon the managers we are
going to talk with the premier league
and the broadcasters because are
involved too so they are going to decide
what is the best for everyone when of
course the wealthy for the players
should be the most important thing and
for the people but when we talk about
the wealthy for the players is the only
country don't accept five substitutions
just three
just three why
so now the the the team is going to have
us to protect the players the players
when we vote to protect the players to
fight five substitutions but it's
much better for everyone for this amount
of games
year by year by year by year the
competition
primarily
while the clubs decide no
so
that's why what they decide the premier
league for manchester city for myself
will be okay
no
no discussions anymore
afternoon pep
how are you there um could i just
confirm team news is everyone fit and
available for the boxing day match
against leicester city
well we had two days off
now we start to training this afternoon
and uh we're going to see because every
day we make tests we do tests and maybe
arrive and say this guy cannot training
is positive or this background stuff is
positive or some injuries or whatever so
i cannot answer you but hopefully as
much as possible
uh you know we'll be ready for the game
on sunday
blessed to go into the game having
beaten newcastle in the league but the
ninth in the table 22 points behind your
side of course they've been hit with
injuries and covid issues also have
played two games less than manchester
city but how surprised are you by their
position in the table
leicester remain lester
for me remain the top quality manager
absolutely with uh
with exceptional players in all
departments but sometimes seasons or
periods the seasons are high and low
sometimes they are
you know
maybe we're used you know to see
leicester all the time up there up there
and it's heads off
how would this club works in many many
senses in recruitment players in
adapt or adjust
many situations but sometimes there are
periods that they are not all the time
consistent consistently happen but
a one game to one game and you see the
quality they have
everything can happen so and remains the
same value i give to them and the same
credit i give to them
because when you see
the quality have a start for the keeper
finishing for body
they are exceptional
but how important is it the way that
players conduct themselves and manage
themselves off the pitch and have you
had to remind the squad of their
responsibilities particularly at this
time of year
in this type of career in our careers
uh the work you do on and off the pitch
is important it's the same
it's so important so demanding
physically mentally you have to be
to you have to live for that profession
all the time every single second
otherwise
there are guys that they are going to
leave every single second this
profession and they are going to sustain
for a longer longer as a profession so
but this
message i gave to them
six years ago every year every month
many many times
so
when
they have to prepare and there are
a lot a lot of players they live in this
way that's why we're consistent
we were consistent fantastically just
this last season
i know nothing is official when it comes
to ferran torres but would you be
disappointed if you left the club in
january
absolutely not
i want the happiness of my players i
said many times i said to him when he
came to me and with many players
if you are not happy you have to leave
he had to stay the people want to live
we are not a club like other clubs like
even they want to live live live and the
ceo and the president say no no no stay
i give my opinion to the club
differently so the guys who want to stay
has to leave another issue is
the agreement between the clubs and
between the players this is not my
business so
the players want to leave but you have
to have an agreement with the with uh
with a club if the club is not
acceptable the offer
whatever they do so
you have to stay but that's why you
the player have a marvelous agents like
they are able to negotiate through the
medias and through the used
underneath or use the
the weapons they have
to do the deals
does they have to do it so but
it's not the case for faran for everyone
so you want to live
because you are not happy here because
you believe you will be more you'll be
happier in another place you have to go
the career for the place
it's short
you know in in one day it's over so
that's why
if if he won't leave absolutely not
disappearing there's a point it is his
desire
and it's a collaborative agreement are
happy for him
afternoon pep um just on the the player
welfare line as well are you as a
manager just given jordan henderson's
comments this week as well are you
finding as a manager
you're having to take an increasingly
active role in looking out for the
well-being of your players
yeah but should be you know the players
or the manager all together and make a
strike or maybe something because if
just for the worse is not going to be
solved because the wafer the fifa the
premier league the broadcasters
the business is more important than the
welfare
the simple example that all around the
world effects institutions here still
three tell me one one
argument to take care to be more welfare
to the players for this one
and here for everyone decide for
themselves we don't do it
so
now i have to discuss about that what
they decide will be okay for me
so it's not necessary to to do it
because
we talk about the welfare it's just for
the players association the players say
okay we don't play anymore until we
solve that situation and after maybe the
people
the people are going to take attention
pay attention but you have to decide for
the broadcaster for the premier league
for the rest to take the decisions on
behalf
for the welfare for the players this is
not going to happen
do you think he could come to that do
you think it could come to a strike
no i don't think so because we want to
play we want to continue you know make
happy the people going to the statement
26 and 27 and 29 and 31st and first and
and and and
and play games so we love to do that you
know it's a i'm not agree complete
there's no reason to make absolutely any
strike but you know when the people say
no
world cups and european cups and and
kind of all cup semi-final two lags and
and
and the
nephilia cups and primarily more teams
and more teams and more games and more
games and less holidays and another one
and we played the first two or three
games to the premier league without
players
and starting them against uh the
community shield against leicester and
tottenham i didn't have the squad we
have ten players eighteen players
he's first for the competition now it's
not fair
it's not fair we play against tottenham
with a lack of lack a lack of
preparation and lack i like good
condition and we lost and we can love
anyway because in sports away always we
lose but we've been being all together
or being just players but
it's not fair why because they're
wearing holidays they have to make
arrests the two three weeks
and now in that moment we we talk about
the welfare for the players in that
moment no
it's your problem my friend
and everyone take a look yourself
hello
i understand what you're saying about
the reasons for allowing for antares to
go because he wants to go and you want
to keep players happy
but how much
do the considerations come in i mean the
pro for instance the progress cole
palmer has made this season how much has
that helped you to make has helped to
smooth the decision to to allow faron to
leave
it's not
i'm thinking what will happen with uh
cole palmer would not be here if iran
would ask to the club to leave he would
allow him or not
so
i think it would be the same
my feeling would have been the same
so
another situation would have been if for
example you have just two or three
attacking players
maybe in that situation for and said
okay i have more chance to play and
maybe i would stay longer so i don't
know
always i have the feeling that when
barcelona and drama they knock the door
for any players it's difficult to say no
so difficult they're still
they are the strongest teams in the
world in terms of fashion in terms of uh
of cities and and many things many
reasons so
and he's from spain and barcelona not
him i understand that
he want to live and when he knocked my
door and said you want to leave i said
leave
so call cheeky
you're a smart agent
try to you know make an agreement if
it's done
and do it and and right moment check it
and text me i hear that it's close
really close
but the club officially my club
officially didn't tell me anything about
pep is already done for on his living
okay
but uh it's the principle so i cannot
that's it many times i cannot push the
players i cannot convince the place to
do something when his mind is away from
here
so it's no sense the other club no no it
doesn't matter what do you do you want
to stay you want to stay you want to
stay i'm not agree with that but every
club decide for
the way he had to decide so this is my
personal absolute opinion
the last couple before the embargo guys
andy hansen at pa
sorry andy we can't hear you i don't
like you sorry sorry hello can you hear
me now
[Music]
sorry yeah pep they're trying to check
on kyle walker please he he's not been
involved for the last few games
he's all right the outright is not fit
and that's why he was not involved
all right is he is he fit now is he okay
to play
did you listen my answer to anita
right okay so
you are not connected you are in the in
the bathroom yeah right
[Laughter]
all right thank you
guys for the embargo if you have a
question for the embargo please raise
your hand now but we'll go
hiya pep just going back to the issue of
three or five substitutions
um will you
raise that with the other managers today
and is
is there going to be
an increase in support do you think for
that measure given that
well do you know how many times do you
know how many times we discuss about the
managers this issue do you know how many
times
no loss
a lot
so
it's enough what else
like nespresso say
what else
so it's not going to happen that in in
your opinion
i have training session in that time so
i don't know who's going to decide they
decide would be good for me
and just in terms of the game in general
have you had a few
positive cases this week and is the game
under threat at all
um nick
the the boxing day one your game against
last time yeah i don't know yeah
i think it was for spawn leads uh
liverpool it was postponed so yeah there
are cases but this is society bold you
know that is not just the premier league
you know you have to primarily have the
virus so it's in everywhere so
i see the newspapers online
every day and i see the headlines rise
the cases rise the cases
restaurants
cancel the dinners for 60 people cancel
is everywhere it's here
so what we want is you know play the
competition fairly and if there are many
cases and with all the clubs like listen
maybe our opponent on the next one of
course
should be
cancelled
you know that but
the same
i know how it works this this this
meetings
everyone looks himself and and that's
all so that's why when they decide the
premier league with the managers will be
okay